# THABO VAN WOUDENBERG

PHYSICAL ACTIVITY | SOCIAL INFLUENCE | MIXED METHODS

#### PERSONALIA

#### SUMMARY STATEMENT

Academic researcher who is interested in social influences on health behaviors and well-being of young people. Likes to use creative and innovative ways to help children and adolescents live a healthy lifestyle. Expert in quantitative methods to analyse large and complex datasets.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### PHD, BEHAVIOURAL SCIENCE

2015-2019

Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL

Dissertation topic: Social network interventions on physical activity in youth.

Promotor: Prof. Dr. Moniek Buijzen Co-promotor: Dr. William Burk Supervisor: Dr. Ir. Kirsten Bevelander

#### MSC, RESEARCH MASTER IN PSYCHOLOGY

2012-2014

Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL

Major research project: The use of narratives to enhance presence in virtual reality.

Supervisors: Prof. Dr. Rick van Baaren, Dr. Matthijs van Leeuwen and Prof. Dr. Moniek Buijzen

Minor research project: Self persuasion to promote media literacy.

Supervisor: Dr. Esther Rozendaal

#### BSC, COMMUNICATION SCIENCE

2009-2012

Communication Science, Radboud University, NL Bachelor thesis: Gamification in scientific research.

Supervisor: Dr. Jan Bosman

## FRESHMAN YEAR MEDICINE

2008-2009

Medical Sciences, Radboud University, NL

#### FRESHMAN YEAR INDUSTRIAL DESIGN

2007-2008

Industrial design, Technical University Delft, NL

# SECONDARY SCHOOL

2001-2007

Stedelijk Gymnasium Nijmegen, NL Field of study: Nature and Health

Extracurricular courses: Latin, Geography, Top sport (hockey)

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### POST DOCTORAL RESEARCHER

2019

Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL Research on physical activity in adolescents

PHD RESEARCHER  Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL  Research for the MyMovez project (ERC grant)	2015-2019
RESEARCH ASSISTANT Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL Preparatory activities for the MyMovez project (ERC grant)	2014-2015
STUDENT ASSISTANT Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, & NHTV, Breda, NL Data collection for a virtual experiment	2013-2014
JUNIOR RESEARCHER  DVJ-Insights, Nijmegen, NL  programming surveys, data analysis and writing reports	2012
TEACHING EXPERIENCE	
MASTHER THESIS SUPERVISOR Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL Master thesis on social network analysis on unhealthy snacking behaviour of youth	2017-2018
BACHELOR THESES SUPERVISOR  Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL  Bachelor thesis on motivation to exercise  Bachelor thesis on brand placement in vlogs  Bachelor thesis on green appeals in advertising  Bachelor thesis on celebrities endorsement and exercise	2017-2018
CURRENT THEORIES OF MEDIA AND INFLUENCE Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL International course on the current theories of influence and media effects Organized fundraisers with the students for the refugees near the university	2015-2018
EXPERIMENTAL DESIGN (LEERPROJECT 3) Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL Course in which the students learn in groups to perform and report an experiment	2016-2017
CURRENT ISSUES IN COMMUNICATION SCIENCE Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL Lecture on virtual reality, fidelity, presence and applications	2016
COMMUNICATION SCIENCE SKILLS  Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL  Course in which the students learn the basic skills for communication scientists  UNIVERSITY AND ACADEMIC SERVICE	2015-2016
RESEARCH GROUPS Social Network group (organizer), Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL	2014-2018

MyMovez group, Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL Young Consumers group, Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL

COMMITTEES

Best thesis award committee of the Behavioural Science Institute

REVIEW

Ad-hoc review for PLOS one

HIRING COMMITTEE

Part of the hiring committee for a PhD position at the Behavioural Science Institute

#### ORGANIZED WORKSHOPS, SYMPOSIA AND COLLOQUIA

Multi-method research in behavioural science: "let's exchange ideas!", Nijmegen 2018

This multidisciplinary symposium introduced the attendants to different methods of data gathering used in behavioural science and gives insights in possible analytical strategies. In the afternoon session, brainstorm sessions were held in which attendants were invited to create innovative research questions based on the MyMovez dataset and set up collaborations to actually carry out the study.

Personalizing psychological assessment and interventions using interactive technology, Nijmegen, 2017

During the symposium, various speakers from different disciplines inspired new ideas on various possible ways we can use interactive technology to personalize psychological assessment and interventions.

During the workshop, we held brainstorm sessions to create new ideas, and promote transdisciplinary collaboration

Tom Snijders - Introduction to Social Network Analyses, Nijmegen, 2015

For this colloquium, we invited one of the leading authorities on social network analysis to present the basic principles and applications of social network theory and social network analysis.

#### **INTERNSHIPS**

RESEARCH INTERN  DVJ-Insights, Nijmegen, NL  Research on 'the Path to Purchase' and 'Gamification'.  Support of the marketing research team	2012
NURSERY INTERN  Jeroen Bosch Ziekenhuis, Den Bosch, NL  Support of the nursery staff	2009
RESEARCH INTERN BMW motorrad, Rijswijk, NL Research on the market position of BMW motor helmets	2007
COURSES AND TRAINING	
COURSES AND TRAINING	
COURSES AND TRAINING  PUBLICATION SKILLS  Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL	2018
PUBLICATION SKILLS	2018

TOWARDS A MORE EFFICIENT AND RELIABLE PSYCHOLOGICAL SCIENCE Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL Workshop taught by Daniel Lakens, Technical University of Eindhoven	2017
PRESENATION SKILLS Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL	2017
UTILISING SOCIAL NETWORKS FOR BEH. CHANGE IN IN COMPLEX INTERV. ISBNPA Conference, Victoria, Canada Workshop taught by Ruth Hunter; Jennifer Bingham, Queen's University Belfast And Kayla de la Haye, University of Southern California	2017
SOCIAL NETWORK APPROACH TO BEHAVIOUR CHANGE Sunbelt Conference, Brighton, England Workshop taught by Thomas Valente, University of Southern California	2015
INTRODUCTION TO RSIENA Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL Workshop taught by Christian Stechlig, University of Groningen	2015
ANALYSES IN R Behavioural Science Institute, Radboud University, NL	2015
INTRODUCTION TO A PHD IN COMMUNICATION SCIENCE ASCOR, University of Amsterdam, NL Workshop taught by Edith Smith, University of Amsterdam	2015

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

H-index Google Scholar: 3

- 7. **Van Woudenberg, T. J.**, Simoski, B., Araújo, E. F. M., Bevelander, K. E., Burk, W. J., Smit, C. R., Buijs, L., Klein, M., & Buijzen, M. (2019). Simulated Social Network Interventions to Promote Physical Activity: Who Should Be the Influence Agents? *Journal of Medical Internet Research*.
- 6. Smit, C. R. de Leeuw, R. N. H., Bevelander, K. E. Burk, W. J., Buijs, L., van Woudenberg, T. J., & Buijzen, M. (2018). An integrated model of fruit, vegetable, and water intake in young adolescents. *Health Psychology*, 37(12), 1159
- 5. Van Woudenberg, T. J., Bevelander, K. E., Burk, W. J., Smit, C. R., Buijs, L., & Buijzen, M. (2018). A randomized controlled trial testing a social network intervention to promote physical activity among adolescents. *BMC Public Health*, 18(1), 542.
- 4. Bevelander, K. E., Smit, C. R., van Woudenberg, T. J., Buijs, L., Burk, W. J., & Buijzen, M. (2018). Youth's social network structures and peer influences: study protocol MyMovez project—Phase I. *BMC Public Health*, 18(1), 504.
- 3. Ketelaar, P. E., Bernritter, S. F., van Woudenberg, T. J., Rozendaal, E., Konig, R. P., Hühn, A. E., ... & Janssen, L. (2018). "Opening" location-based mobile ads: How openness and location congruency of location-based ads weaken negative effects of intrusiveness on brand choice. *Journal of Business Research*, 91, 277-285.
- 2. Fernandes de Mello Araujo, E., Simoski, B., van Woudenberg, T. J., Bevelander, K. E., Smit, C. R., Buijs, L. B., ... & Buijzen, M. A. (2018). Using simulations for exploring interventions in social networks: Modeling physical activity behaviour in Dutch school classes. In *Proceedings of 8th International Conference on Simulation and Modeling Methodologies, Simultech 2018*, Porto, Portugal, 29-31 July, 2018.
- 1. Ketelaar, P. E., Bernritter, S. F., van't Riet, J., Hühn, A. E., van Woudenberg, T. J., Müller, B. C., & Janssen, L. (2017). Disentangling location-based advertising: the effects of location congruency and medium type on consumers' ad attention and brand choice. International *Journal of Advertising*, 36(2), 356-367.

#### CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

# INSNA CONFERENCE, MONTREAL, CANADA 2019 Promoting Adolescents Physical Activity through Social Network Interventions ISBNPA CONFERENCE, PRAGUE, CZECK REPUBLIC 2019 Simulated Social Network Interventions to Promote Physical Activity: Who Should Be the Influence Agents? ETMAAL CONFERENCE, NIJMEGEN, THE NETHERLANDS 2019 Narratives in the virtual world: on Presence, Involvement and Transportation in a Virtual Reality Game. ISPAH CONFERENCE, LONDON, UK 2018 Testing a Social Network Vlog Intervention to Promote Physical Activity Among Adolescents: A Randomized Controlled Trial. HEPA CONFERENCE, ZAGREB, CROATIA 2017 A Randomized Controlled Trial Testing a Social Network Intervention to Promote Physical Activity Among Adolescents by using Smartphones. ISBNPA CONFERENCE, VICTORIA, CANADA 2017 Similarity of physical activity in youngsters' social networks: Selection or Influence? ISPAH CONFERENCE, BANGKOK, THAILAND 2016 Assessing influence of peer interaction on physical activity among youth by measuring peer proximity with mobile technology. BSI PHD DAY, NIJMEGEN, NL 2015 Social network implemented health campaign to promote physical activity among youth. ICA CONFERENCE, SAN JUAN, PUERTO RICO 2015 To be there, or not to be there: Transportation, Involvement, and Presence in Virtual Reality. ETMAAL CONFERENCE, ANTWERP, BELGIUM Narratives in the virtual world: on Presence, Involvement and Transportation in a Virtual Reality Game. **INVITED TALKS** BSI DAY, GROESBEEK, NL 2017 Social network intervention to promote physical activity in youth. ACHC MOBILE HEALTH, AMSTERMDAG, NL 2017 MyMovez Wearable Lab: 'All the gear, but no idea!' 'GYMMEN IN DE TOEKOMST' CONFERENCE, PAPENDAL, NL 2015

#### AWARDS AND NOMINATIONS

MyMovez: Health campaign using wearables

The use of mobile technology to promote physical activity and health.

CONTEMPORARY CHALLENGES, CONFERENCE, NIJMEGEN, NL

2015

BEST PAPER ISBNPA Conference, Prague, Czech Republic Last round	2019
BEST PAPER  BSI day, Groesbeek, NL  Second prize	2018
BEST STUDENT PAPER SIMULTECH, Porto, Portugal nominated	2018
BEST PRESENTATION ISBNPA Conference, Victoria, Canada Top three	2017
INNOVATION AWARD  ISPAH Conference, Bangkok, Thailand  Last round	2016

### SKILLS

#### DATA ANALYSES

Expert in advanced analytical techniques (e.g. Mixed effects models, Social network analyses) in R.

Expert in data handling (transforming structures, merging m multilevel imputation) in R

Advanced in data visualizations (e.g. ggplot, ggraph, photoshop)

Familiar with other analytical software (e.g. SPSS, Lisrel, Intellex)

Intermediate programmer of psychological experiment (PsychoPy) in python.

#### PROJECT MANAGEMENT

Approach schools for participation in research projects.

Stay in touch with contact person of the school, and schedule data collections.

Taking care of the inventory and the research material.

Keep track of participation a large sample of participants (ca. 1500) over multiple time periods

### KNOWLEDGE DISSEMINATION

Building websites (Wordpress or R Blogdown) to keep in touch with (parents of) participants to receive consent and keep them up to date about the research projects.

Present research findings on (inter)national conference and participating schools.

Writing scientific articles for international scientific journals (in word and latex).

Collaboration with other departments or disciplines.

THABO VAN WOUDENBERG

THABOVW@GMAIL.COM

KAAPSTANDER 102 • 6541EX, NIJMEGEN • (+31) 6 38641317